Bart Bok collection, 1928-1983
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Bart Bok collection, 1928-1983
MS 403
Bok, Bart Jan, 1906-
The Bart Bok collection (1928-1983) documents his astronomical research, instruction and administration at Harvard University, the Australian National University, the University of Arizona and associated observatories. The collection includes material relevant to the study of galactic structure and dynamics and interstellar matter, with particular emphasis on: The Milky Way, Dark Nebulae, Star Formation, Spiral Structure of the Galaxy, Star Clouds of Magellan and Radio Astronomy. The bulk of the collection is comprised of correspondence (1945-1983), and includes biographical, research, professional and public lecture, instruction, subject, publication and photograph files.
17.5 linear feet (Approximately 35,000 items)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Bart Bok (1906-1983) was an accomplished astronomer, educator and administrator. Born in Hoorn, Holland in 1906, he studied at the University of Leiden and the University of Groningen, where he earned a Ph.D. in 1932. He married astronomer Priscilla Fairfield Bok, Ph.D. (1896-1975), in 1929, and had two children. He served as R.W. Willson Fellow in Astronomy at Harvard University from 1927-1929, Professor of Astronomy at this same institution from 1933-1957, and Associate Director of the Harvard Observatory from 1946-1952. Dr. Bok and his family lived in Canberra, Australia, from 1957-1966, where he served as the Director of the Mount Stromlo Observatory and Professor of Astronomy at the Australian National University. Dr. Bok was appointed as Director of the Steward Observatory and Head of the Department of Astronomy at the University of Arizona from 1966-1970, where he served as Professor of Astronomy until his retirement in 1974. He was Professor Emeritus of Astronomy at the University of Arizona from 1974-1983.
Dr. Bok focused his research primarily on galactic structure and dynamics and stellar and interstellar matter. He was a recognized authority on The Milky Way and contributed significantly to galactic astronomy by emphasizing the importance and applications of radio astronomy. Particular areas of interest included the following: Dark Nebulae, Star Formation, Spiral Structure of the Galaxy, and Star Clouds of Magellan. His numerous publications on these subjects attest to a long and prolific research and writing career. Dr. Bok was elected as a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1939 and as an associate of the Royal Astronomical Society in 1971. In addition to his work as a research scientist and academic instructor, Dr. Bok was dedicated to educating the public, including youth audiences, through popular lectures in astronomy. He and his wife, Priscilla Fairfield Bok, also shared an interest in promoting careers in astronomy for women.
Organization
This Collection is organized into eight series. Two series contain subseries: Research Files and Photographs.
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1928-1983
Series 2: Correspondence Files, 1945-1983
Series 3: Research Files, 1944-1983
Subseries: Reports, 1947-1983
Subseries: Grant Proposals, 1967-1981
Subseries: Notes, 1944-1979
Series 4: Professional and Public Lecture Files, 1945-1983
Series 5: Instruction Files, 1936-1974
Series 6: Publication Files, 1928-1983
Series 7: Subject Files, 1968-1982
Series 8: Photographs, 1933-1982
Subseries: Stellar Objects, 1950-1982
Subseries: Facilities and Equipment, 1933-1980
Subseries: General, 1944-1979
Subseries: Negatives and Slides, 1951-1980
Subseries: Oversize, 1971-1978
Scope and Content Note
The Bart Bok papers (1928-1983) document his astronomical research, instruction and administration at Harvard University, the Australian National University and the University of Arizona and associated observatories. The collection includes materials on galactic structure and dynamics and interstellar matter, with particular emphasis on the following topics: The Milky Way, Dark Nebula, Star Formation, Spiral Structure of the Galaxy, Star Clouds of Magellan and Radio Astronomy. The material includes biographical information, personal communications and professional correspondence with renowned colleagues throughout the world, research notes and notebooks that include international observational data, professional and public lectures, instruction and subject files, as well as publications and photographs. Please note that dates listed reflect the subject content of the material.
Bok, Bart Jan, 1906-1983; Bok, Bart Jan, 1906-1983 -- Archives; Bok, Bart Jan, 1906-1983 -- Correspondence; Astronomy -- Study and teaching; Stars -- Evolution; Galaxies -- Evolution; Galactic dynamics; Milky Way; Nebulae; Interstellar matter; Magellanic Clouds; Dark matter (Astronomy); Radio Astronomy; Sagan, Carl, 1934-1996 -- Correspondence; Kitt Peak National Observatory; University of Arizona. Steward Observatory; Mount Stromlo Observatory; Astronomy Charts, diagrams, etc.; Astronomy -- Pictorial works
Container List
- Series 1: Biographical Files, 1928-1983, .42 linear feet (Approximately 840 items).
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Biographical files document Dr. Bok's professional recognition and achievements as a researcher, instructor and administrator. Includes personal and professional recollections and discussions of significant developments in the field of astronomy, during the early to late-twentieth century. The life and career of his wife, astronomer Priscilla Fairfield Bok, are also documented in this series.
  - Awards and Certificates. 1939-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies. 1927-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bok, Bart. 1956-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bok, Bart: Chapter Sixteen, Last Years. undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bok, Bart: Memoir, Biographical Memoirs of the National Academy of Science, 64. undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bok, Bart: Oral History, American Institute of Physics, General Information. 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bok, Bart: Oral History, American Institute of Physics, Session I (later II), Rough Draft. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bok, Bart: Oral History, American Institute of Physics, Session II. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bok, Bart: Oral History, American Institute of Physics, Session III, Rough Draft. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bok, Bart: Oral History, American Institute of Physics, Session IV. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bok, Priscilla. 1928-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guest Book. 1957-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Correspondence Files, 1945-1983, 6.07 linear feet (Approximately 12,140 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Correspondence files primarily document Dr. Bok's professional communication with renowned astronomy colleagues and friends throughout the world. Also included is personal correspondence with family members and friends of Drs. Bart and Priscilla Bok.
  - A.. 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Abt, Helmut. 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Astronomical Society. 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Arizona Sonora Desert Museum. 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Arp, Halton C. 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Astrology. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Astrology. 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Astrology. 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - B. 1945-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - B. 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Baade, Walter. 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bappu, M.K. Vainu. 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Barchas, Sam and Cecile. 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bateson, Frank. 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Blanco, Victor M. 1967-1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Blitz, Leo. 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Burbidge, Geoffrey and Margaret. 1971-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - C. 1945-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - C. 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chamberlain, Joseph M. 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Committee for the Scientific Investigation of Claims of the Paranormal. 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - D. 1946-1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - D. 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dickman, Bob. 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dixon, Robert. 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - E. 1946-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Erro, Luis Enrique. 1944-1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - F. 1972-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fehrenbach, Charles. 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Flanagan, Dennis. 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fleischer, Dr. Robert. 1947-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fraknoi, Andrew. 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Frederick, Larry. 1974-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - G. 1955-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - G. 1957-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Gingerich, Owen. 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Glaspey, John. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Goldberg, Leo. 1970-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Graham, John. 1962-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - H. 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - H. 1972-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University Press. 1973-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hintzen, Paul M. 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hoag, Arthur. 1949-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - I. 1973-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - J. 1955-1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - K. 1972-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - K. 1977-1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - L. 1955-1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - L. 1968-1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Levy, David. 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lowell Observatory. 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Lynga, Gosta. 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - McGraw-Hill. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - M. 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - M. 1971-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - M. 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Miller, Ellis. 1975-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Miller, Freeman D. 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Muzzio, Juan Carlos. 1976-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - N. 1974-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences. 1969-1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - National Academy of Sciences, U.S.S.R.-Soviet Scientists. 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - National Science Foundation. 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Northern Arizona University. 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - O. 1960-1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Oliphant, Sir Mark. 1970-1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Oort, Jan. 1970-1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - P. 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - P. 1969-1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - P. 1972-1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - P. 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - P. 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Payne-Gaposhkin, Cecelia. 1954-1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Personal. 1965-1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Personal. 1971-1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Personal. 1972-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Personal. 1975-1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Q. 1971-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - R. 1967-1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - R. 1972-1978 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - R. 1972-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - R. 1972-1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - R. 1973-1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Rawlings, Dennis. 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Reipurth, Bo. 1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - S. 1955-1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - S. 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - S. 1972-1977 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - S. 1972-1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - S. 1972-1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - S. 1974-1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - S. 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - S. 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Sagan, Dr. Carl. 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Schweighauser, Charles A. 1974-1982 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Shapely, Harlow. 1970-1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Smith, Lindsey. 1972-1977 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Starfield, Sumner. 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - T. 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - T. 1972-1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - U. 1967-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Upgren, Arthur R. 1976-1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - V. 1970-1978 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - V. 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - V. 1972-1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - W. 1968-1983 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - W. 1971-1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - W. 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - W. 1972-1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - W. 1973-1982 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Weaver, A.B. 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Weaver, Bruce. 1971-1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - White, P. 1972-1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - White, Raymond. 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Wood, Harley. 1972-1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Y. 1972-1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified. 1955-1983 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Z. 1971-1982 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Research Files, 1944-1983, 2.94 linear feet (Approximately 5,880 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Research files are divided into three subseries: Reports (1947-1983), Grant Proposals (1967-1981) and Notes (1944-1979). Reports include reports authored by Dr. Bok relevant to his administrative appointments, co-authored reports on various astronomical topics, and reports written by colleagues and former students. Grant Proposals include submissions by Dr. Bok on various research topics as well as those authored by colleagues. Notes include observational notes and notebooks belonging to Dr. Bart Bok, Dr. Priscilla Bok, and colleagues.
  - Subseries: Reports, 1947-1983
    - Ad Hoc Advisory Panel for Large Radio Astronomy Facilities, National Science Foundation. 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Albrecht, Rudolf, Bart J. Bok and Greg Cozza, Stars on the Far Side of Globule Hawarden 2. 1977 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Anders, Edward, Insterstellar Molecules, Formation in Solar Nebulae. 1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Annual-Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory. 1959 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Annual-Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory. 1963 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Annual-Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory. 1965 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Annual-Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory. 1966 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy Mount Stromlo Observatory Report for the Parliament. 1965 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory. 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory. 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory. 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory. 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Annual-Department of Astronomy and Steward Observatory. 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Annual-Summary for Annual Report. 1974 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Astronomy in Arizona. 1968 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Blitz, Leo, Milky Way Spiral Structure: A New Look. 1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Buhl, David, Chemical Constituents of Interstellar Clouds. 1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Buhl, David, Interstellar Molecules and the Origin of Life. 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Carina Spiral Feature. 1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Cordwell, Carolyn S., A Study of Dark Nebulae. 1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Department of Astronomy Science Development Program. 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Department of Astronomy Science Development Program, National Science Foundation. 1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Eclipse-Related Tour of the USSR. 1981 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - First-Hand Account of the Personal Equation Problem. 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Formation of Stars and Solar Systems. 1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Galactic Structure in the Vela-Puppis, Carina Centaurus, Circinius and Norma Sections of the Milky Way. 1973 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Programs in Physics and Astronomy. 1978 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Gum Nebula. 1971 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Cursory Survey of Optical Testing Methods. 1947 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Stellar Radiometry. 1949 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Systemic Motion of the Local B0-B5 Stars<5m.26. 1949 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - How to Calculate the Particle Mass of a Globule with Radius R (in parsecs), Absorbing Vm (ptg) Magnitudes. 1970 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - International Astronomical Union Commission 33, Structure and Dynamics of the Galaxy, Draft. 1967 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - IAU Commission 33. 1972 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - IAU Commission 33. 1981 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - IAU Commission 34. 1972 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Jobs in Astronomy, A Guide to the Ph.D. or M.A. in Astronomy Looking for a Position. 1972 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Lodge at Siding Spring Observatory. 1965 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Lowell Observatory. 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Notes Relating to the Proposed British Large Telescope. 1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - NSF-Section on Astronomy on the First Phase of the Work Done Under NSF Grant 7782. 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - President's Report, American Astronomical Society. 1973. Box 18 Folder 6 Problems of Galactic Spiral Structure. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Progress of Photo-Electric Work at Boyden Station. 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Recent Development at Steward Observatory (I) and What Has Been Accomplished (II). 1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Red Emulsion Eastman Kodak 098-01. 1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Research Activities at Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory. 1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Second Meeting of the Ad Hoc Advisory Panel for Large Radio Astronomy Facilities, National Science Foundation 1969 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Star Birth in Our Galaxy. 1980 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - University Corporation for Atmospheric research to National Science Foundation. 1973 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - University of Arizona Science Development Program. 1968 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Untitled. 1983 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Subseries: Grant Proposals, 1967-1981
    - Monterey Institute for Research in Astronomy, Oliver Challenge Grant. 1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Office of Naval Research, Photometric Studies of the Magellanic Clouds. 1967 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Far Infrared Photometry of Conspicuous Globules. 1979 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - National Science Foundation, Blue Stars at Low Galactic Altitudes. 1971 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - National Science Foundation, Blue Stars at Low Galactic Altitudes. 1973 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Subseries: Notes, 1944-1979
    - American Astronomy Society. 1970 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Barnard Objects. 1975 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Barnard Objects. 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Bok, Bart and Myron Smith. 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Bok/Smith, 8-Color Borgman, Catalina Station. 1966 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Bok/Smith, Monoceros and Cepheus. 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Bok, Priscilla, Book 3: 50" Telescope-Mt. Stromlo Observatory, Australia. 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Bok, Priscilla, Mt. Stromlo Observatory, Canberra, A.C.T., Australia, Observational Data. 1959-1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Butcher, Harvey-Magellanic Clouds and Photometry. 1976 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Catalina Station. 1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Cepheus (LF4) Field, Finding Chart and Prints. 1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Cerro Tololo. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Cerro Tololo, 16-inch Reflector. 1971 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory, Chile, Observing Plans. 1978 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Harvard. undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Astronomy 4. 1947 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Astronomy 7A Book I. 1947 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Astronomy 7A Book II. 1947 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Astrononmy 211: Stellar Motions and Galacticy Dynamics. 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Observed Rotation of External Galaxies, Astronomy 211. 1948 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Hoag, Arthur, Transfer of Radiation in Stellar Atmosphere Absorption Lines in Stellar Spectra Internal Constitution. 1947 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - IAU Symposium 85-87. 1979 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Indeterminate Observational. undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Kitt Peak Observatory-Monoceros and Cepheus Sky Readings. 1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Kitt Peak Observatory-Observational Data. 1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Milky Way in Puppis-Tonanzintla. 1944 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Monoceros Field. 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Mt. Brignan, Australia. 1966-1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Mount Stromlo Record Book I. 1966-1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Observational. undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Observational data and Correspondence. ca. 1950 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Observations. 1960 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Observations and Correspondence. 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Observing Program. 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Siding Spring Observatory, Book 2. 1965 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Southern Spiral Structure. 1962 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Steward Observatory-36-inch Telescope. 1966 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - SUNY at Stonybrook, Summer Institute for Astronomy and Physics. 1968 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Wide-field Photometer Bingar-Large Magellanic Cloud and Young Associations. 1961 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series 4: Professional and Public Lecture Files, 1945-1983, 1.68 linear feet (Approximately 3,360 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Professional and public Lecture Files include Dr. Bok's professional and public lectures on galactic structure and dynamics, interstellar matter, and research advances in astronomy.
  - A Bigger and Better Milky Way-Audio Tape. 1981 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Brief Popular Summaries, Globule, Spiral Structure, Globular Clusters, Astrophysics, Populations I and II. undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Distances and Extinction of Dark Nebulae. 1979 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - General. 1945-1952 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - General. 1954-1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - General. 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - General. 1964 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - General. 1965 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - General. 1966-1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - General. 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - General. 1970 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - General. 1971 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - General. 1972-1974 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - General. 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - General. 1975-1978 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - General. 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - General. 1980 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - General. 1981 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - General. 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - General. 1983 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - General. undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - General Luminosity Function. 1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - The Promise of the Space Telescope-Audio Tape. 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Science Makes News-Broadcasts I-IV. 1963-1964 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Distances, Double Stars, Distances in the Milky Way, Velocity of Light. undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Summary of a Lecture Before the Junior Astronomy Club- New York. 1942 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Three Weeks of Symposia. 1953 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Instruction Files, 1936-1974, 1.26 linear feet (Approximately 2,520 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Instruction Files include material related to Dr. Bok's instruction at Harvard University, the Australian National University and the University of Arizona. Course and seminar notes and syllabi relevant to general astronomy, stellar and interstellar matter, galactic structure and dynamics and radio astronomy are included.
  - Astronomy 3, Practical Astronomy, Harvard. 1949-1956 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Astronomy 7A, Examinations. 1940-1948 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Astronomy 200, Introduction to Stellar Astronomy. 1967-1972 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Astronomy 210, Stellar Distributions. 1949-1956 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Astronomy 210, Stellar Distributions. 1956 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Astronomy 211, Galactic Dynamics. 1952-1970 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Astronomy 211, Stellar Motions and Galactic Dynamics. 1952-1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Astronomy 211, Stellar Motions and Galactic Dynamics. 1952-1973 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy 211, Stellar Motions and Galactic Dynamics. 1967-1973 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Astronomy 211, Stellar Motions and Galactic Dynamics- Index to Lectures. 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 1)